♪Drink frost♪
♪喝霜♪
♪Hold tight to your roots♪
♪紧紧抓住你的根♪
♪This land♪
♪这片土地♪
♪Chasing the Waves♪
♪追逐海浪♪
♪My leaves blow past♪
♪我的树叶被风吹过♪
♪The Border of Ten Thousand Miles♪
♪万里境界♪
♪Looking at each other far away♪
♪远远地看着对方♪
♪At the other end is♪
♪另一端是♪
♪Forever and ever♪
♪永远永远♪
♪When we meet and say goodbye♪
♪当我们相遇并告别时♪
♪When you're snuggled away♪
♪当你依偎着的时候♪
♪I never forget♪
♪我永远不会忘记♪
♪The Shadow of the Lightsaber♪
♪光剑之影♪
♪Draw through the blemishes of the sky♪
♪画出天空的瑕疵♪
♪Ok Dream♪
♪好梦♪
♪Broken in the wind♪
♪在风中破碎♪
♪Beat the wind and surf♪
♪乘风破浪♪
♪Watch thousands of ships crossing over♪
♪观看数千艘船只穿越♪
♪The sea and rice fields change♪
♪大海和稻田的变化♪
♪Military uniform, women's uniform, Loi Fong♪
♪军装、女装、莱坊♪
♪Once drank ice, blood didn't get cold, dreamed of exploring the Leyou fields♪
♪喝了冰，血不冷， 梦想探索乐游田野♪
♪Wishing only you by my side♪
♪愿只有你在我身边♪
♪No offense to Saengwasan♪
♪无意冒犯生瓦山♪
♪Tree soaring to the sky, roots intertwined, traveling to the ends of the earth beside you♪
♪树参天，树根缠绕， 与你同行♪
♪Look at the fireflies sitting on our shoulders♪
♪看看我们肩上的萤火虫♪
♪No regrets in the mundane♪
♪平凡中无怨无悔♪
=The sky's love is close to my heart=
=天空的爱靠近我的心=
=Episode 12=
=第12集=
(Letter to Cui Lin)
（给崔琳的信）
The commander has returned.
指挥官回来了。
sir
先生
What is the situation in Yingzhou?
瀛州的情况怎么样？
The commander's father suddenly became ill.
指挥官的父亲突然病了。
There's nothing wrong with the seal.
封印没有什么问题。
Tootsin recalled.
图辛回忆道。
Tutsin was Father's confidant.
图辛是父亲的知己。
He was attacked and injured along the way.
途中他遭到袭击并受伤。
After delivering the letter
送完信后
He fell down and died.
他摔倒死了。
sir
先生
Sir, an old disease has recurred.
先生，旧病又复发了。
Or were they poisoned?
还是他们中毒了？
It was not written in the letter.
信中并没有写到。
Sir, please allow me
先生，请允许我
Take the cavalry on a journey
带着骑兵去旅行
Go get help immediately.
立即去寻求帮助。
It was related to Father's safety.
这关系到父亲的安危。
I will go with you.
我和你一起去。
cannot
不能
The army has a lot of baggage.
军队有很多行李。
It's not convenient to move quickly.
快速移动并不方便。
It would be better for you to continue following the original plan.
你最好继续按照原来的计划进行。
Bring the army back to support quickly.
赶紧调集军队回来支援。
One more thing
还有一件事
Your body has not yet recovered.
你的身体还没有恢复。
urgent movement several days and nights in a row
连续几天几夜紧急行动
Your body won't be able to take it.
你的身体将无法承受。
Ah Ying, I've made up my mind.
阿莹，我已经决定了。
you and me
你和我
Take the cavalry to join together first.
带着骑兵先会合。
No need to argue anymore.
没必要再争论了。
can
能
Respect the Viceroy
尊重总督
Saluting to the Viceroy
向总督致敬
Your three children
你的三个孩子
After receiving the letter you wrote
收到你写的信后
Li Jun and Li Lai were quite grateful.
李俊和李莱颇为感激。
Hurry and promise to retreat immediately.
赶紧答应立刻撤退。
Send the letter back
将信寄回
Please let me take good care of you.
请让我好好照顾你。
As for Li
至于李
I couldn't imagine that he would slit his neck.
我无法想象他会割断自己的脖子。
Zheng Guogong's people then sent their heads back.
郑国公的人这才送了回去。
(Letter to Viceroy Sun) Plus one letter attached.
（给孙总督的信） 另附一封信。
(I'm not the eldest son.)
（我不是长子。）
(If you kill your father)
（如果你杀了你父亲）
(I must thank you for being emperor.)
（我必须感谢你成为皇帝。）
Li Ni called himself the emperor.
李妮自称皇帝。
Of course, it must be inherited. Becoming Emperor after his real father
当然，它必须继承。 继他的亲生父亲之后成为皇帝
Prince Liang
梁亲王
This is a great auspicious matter.
这是一件大吉大利的事情。
If I have an idea
如果我有一个想法
To betray like this
就这样背叛
Let the lightning strike
让闪电击中
You ungrateful son has slandered me.
你这个忘恩负义的儿子，竟然污蔑我。
You ungrateful son, you are slandering me.
你这个忘恩负义的儿子，你这是在污蔑我。
The Viceroy is brilliant.
总督很聪明。
Go call the royal doctor.
去叫御医吧。
See what happened.
看看发生了什么。
Please accept it.
请接受。
Find a way to let Hu Yin Weiguo know.
想办法让胡尹卫国知道。
Yes, sir.
是的先生。
Viceroy
总督
Duke Liang's body had always been weak.
梁公的身体一向虚弱。
Plus he has heart arrhythmia.
另外他还有心律失常。
Moments later, the mood turned violent.
片刻之后，气氛变得激烈起来。
There are indications of cerebrovascular disease.
有脑血管疾病的迹象。
I'm afraid
我耽心
I fear that this disease will be a crisis.
我担心这种疾病将是一场危机。
Can it help?
有帮助吗？
I'm not sure.
我不知道。
Please take it away.
请把它拿走。
Take it easy.
别紧张。
You have to take it easy.
你必须放轻松。
Don't let it hit.
别让它撞到。
If you hit it, you'll run out of air.
如果你击中它，你就会耗尽空气。
Shi Chi Lang Shi Chi Lang
Shi Chi Lang Shi Chi Lang
Urgent report from Luoyang
来自洛阳的紧急报告
From the investigation of military scouts
来自军事侦察兵的调查
Cavalry under Duke Linzhi
Cavalry under Duke Linzhi
have abnormal movements
有异常动作
A detachment of cavalry carried heavy crossbows.
一队骑兵携带重弩。
Leave the Luo River unknown trace
留下洛水不为人知的痕迹
incorrect
不正确
One cavalry soldier carried a heavy crossbow.
一名骑兵手持重弩。
It's not like leaving Luoyang.
这不像离开洛阳。
More like an ambush.
更像是一场伏击。
Who do they want to assassinate?
他们想刺杀谁？
Enemy attacks
敌人攻击
There's an enemy sneaking up on you.
有一个敌人正在偷袭你。
Sanlang
Sanlang
This time swept them clean and there was nothing left.
这一次把他们扫干净了，什么都没有留下。
Cuilin
库林
I'll wait and see.
我会拭目以待。
This time you will still be alive.
这次你还活着。
Survive or not?
生存还是不生存？
sir
先生
Chen thing
陈事
Ah Ying
阿英
sir
先生
Ah-ying Ah-ying
阿英阿英
Please bear with me.
请多多包涵。
How are you
你好吗
kill
杀
wade
韦德
Can't go on.
无法继续。
The Zhenxi army has arrived.
镇西军已至。
It's Li.
是李。
Li here came to help.
李来帮忙。
what?
什么？
Is it Li Ni again?
又是李妮吗？
sir
先生
go
去
Let me take a look at Cui Lin and Zhao He.
我再看看崔琳和赵赫。
Or just run away?
还是直接逃跑？
You shouldn't go looking for trouble with the Zhenxi Army.
你不该去找镇西军的麻烦。
The person Li Ni sent
李妮派来的人
They were all excellent soldiers.
他们都是优秀的士兵。
Even if we can borrow soldiers
就算可以借兵
But it would be too damaging.
但这会造成太大的伤害。
We can't go and negotiate.
我们不能去谈判。
Sanlang
Sanlang
As long as there is life
只要还有生命
There must be hope.
一定有希望。
what happened
发生了什么
Why did you bring her back?
你为什么把她带回来？
Hurry and call a military doctor.
赶紧叫军医来。
fast
快速地
And are you injured or not?
还有你有没有受伤？
The arrowhead went in too deep.
箭头插得太深了。
Plus it has thorns.
而且它还有刺。
If you pull it out violently
如果用力拔出
I'm afraid it will hurt my meridians.
我怕会伤到我的经脉。
And the blood will not stop flowing.
并且血液不会停止流动。
now
现在
You can only pierce the arrow's head. Come out carefully
你只能刺穿箭头。 小心点出来
I'm old.
我老了。
Hands are not steady, not daring to pierce
手不稳不敢刺
It's okay. I know medicine.
没关系。我懂医学。
Let me do it.
让我来做吧。
But this method is very painful.
但这种方法非常痛苦。
I'm afraid that this little lady won't be able to stand it.
恐怕这个小女人受不了了。
Ah Ying
阿英
The doctor said it would have to be drilled.
医生说必须要打孔。
Take out the arrowhead.
取出箭头。
It'll hurt a bit.
会有点痛。
Can you bear it?
你能忍受吗？
I'm there.
我在那里。
You'll be fine.
你会没事的。
Mr. Kong, please endure the pain.
孔先生，请忍痛。
Please bear with me.
请多多包涵。
It'll be finished soon.
很快就会完成的。
It's almost there.
快到了。
Bite me, bite me
咬我，咬我
nevermind
没关系
It's okay now. It's okay.
现在没事了。没关系。
It's okay.
没关系。
It's okay now.
现在没事了。
Let me help you wipe it.
让我帮你擦吧。
The valley's terrain is very dangerous.
山谷地势十分险峻。
Do you know?
你知道吗？
How many soldiers were the other side hiding?
对方究竟隐藏了多少士兵？
One more thing
还有一件事
The other party held a heavy crossbow.
对方手持重弩。
You can survive.
你可以生存。
It is considered kindness.
这被认为是仁慈。
The greatness that heaven has for you
天堂为你准备的伟大
Shi Chi Lang
Shi Chi Lang
Polite people will stay away from danger.
有礼貌的人会远离危险。
You are a good general.
你是一位好将军。
Why did you imitate?
为什么要模仿？
Your uncle died like that.
你叔叔就这样死了。
Just refer to textbooks.
参考一下课本就可以了。
Sit and discuss academics all day.
整天坐下来讨论学术。
Just now, we had just attacked Dan Tong.
刚才，我们刚刚攻击了丹童。
according to plan
根据计划
It was an important moment in retaking the capital.
这是夺回首都的重要时刻。
If you have an accident
如果您发生意外
What will you have me do?
你要我做什么？
One more thing
还有一件事
The commander looked at that.
指挥官看着这一幕。
She was a member of the Chui Family Army.
她是崔家军的一员。
You will risk your life.
你将冒着生命危险。
Why to help her?
为什么要帮她？
Who said I'm going to help?
谁说我要帮忙？
Mr. Kong He Kan
Mr. Kong He Kan
You can't...
你不能...
I went to help Young Master Chui.
我去帮助崔少爷了。
Do you think I believe you?
你以为我相信你吗？
I think you believe
我想你相信
okay
好的
Whatever you say is right.
不管你说什么都是对的。
You guys
你们
No.
不。
You people, who are you?
你们这些人，你们是谁？
I couldn't imagine that Li Ni would dare to kill my younger brother.
我无法想象李妮竟然敢杀我弟弟。
How dare he kill my salesman?
他怎么敢杀我的推销员？
Now I will kill you.
现在我要杀了你。
To atone for my brother's life
为我兄弟赎罪
Hu Yin
Hu Yin
I never thought that your child
我没想到你的孩子
Will you dare to kill my brother?
你敢杀我兄弟吗？
Now I will kill you.
现在我要杀了你。
Our men were able to stop Hu Yin Weiguo in time.
我们的人及时阻止了胡尹卫国。
The Royal Doctor also knew what to say.
御医也知道该说什么。
Her Majesty trusts
女王陛下信任
The Viceroy arrived.
总督来了。
Viceroy, please punish me for my inability.
总督，请惩罚我的无能。
Prince Liang was too frightened.
梁王太害怕了。
His original pulse was already weak.
他原本的脉搏已经微弱。
Especially now
尤其是现在
Just now, it was because of Hu Yin's anger.
刚才，是因为胡殷的愤怒。
Can't breathe for a long time
长时间无法呼吸
The heart nerve has broken.
心脏神经断了。
Medicine and stone needles are not effective.
药物和砭石没有效果。
Has passed away, please.
已经去世了，请。
I, I want to cut off his head.
我，我想砍下他的头。
and sent it to his son
并寄给他的儿子
Let his son have a taste.
让儿子也尝尝。
What is it called? Pain like stabbing thorns
这叫什么？ 疼痛如刺痛
This person dies, no regrets.
此人死了，无怨无悔。
Turn off the news
关掉新闻
Take his bones and burn them.
把他的骨头拿下来烧掉。
Destroy the bones.
毁掉骨头。
Revenge for Zheng Guogong
Revenge for Zheng Guogong
no
不
I want to cut off his head.
我想砍下他的头。
and sent it to his son
并寄给他的儿子
You hit me.
你打我。
I didn't think that he would slap me.
我没想到他会打我。
Hu Yin Hu Yin
Hu Yin Hu Yin
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Duke Liang is dead.
梁公死了。
what?
什么？
Li Ni beheaded
李妮斩首
Zheng Guogong's and sent it back.
Zheng Guogong's and sent it back.
Hu Yin Weiguo was so sad and angry that he couldn't stand it.
胡尹卫国悲愤难忍。
Strangling Prince Liang to death
绞杀梁王
Therefore, this news must be quickly suppressed.
所以，这个消息必须赶紧压制下去。
Can't let Li Ni know.
不能让李妮知道。
that Prince Liang is dead
梁王死了
I only know Hu Yin Weiguo.
我只认识胡尹卫国。
Stupid and messy
又蠢又乱
Unthinkable
难以想象
That she would ruin my big plans.
她会破坏我的大计划。
This Li Ni had an indomitable personality.
这个李妮，性格不屈不挠。
clever and cunning
聪明狡猾
Let Prince Liang still be alive.
让梁王还活着。
He didn't back down.
他没有退缩。
Viceroy, don't get upset.
总督您别生气。
Marry a virtuous wife
娶一个贤惠的妻子
I married the wrong wife.
我娶错了老婆。
to lose Luo Yang
to lose Luo Yang
Although this is the case
虽然是这样的情况
Even if she makes another mistake
即使她再犯一个错误
Viceroy
总督
I never did anything to her.
我从来没有对她做过任何事。
Probably the wife who shares the suffering
可能是分担痛苦的妻子
In the end, it is something different in your mind.
到最后，你心里的想法是不一样的。
What are you again?
你又是什么？
She is your righteous wife.
她是你的正义妻子。
I just don't like her.
我只是不喜欢她。
You know that in my heart
你知道在我心里
My wife is only you.
我的妻子只有你一个人。
Stop, stop, stop.
停下来，停下来，停下来。
It's here.
它在这里。
Hurry and burn it.
赶紧烧掉吧。
Ordered from above
从上面订购
You have to break the bones and scatter them.
你必须把骨头打碎，把它们打散。
Please, please.
拜托，拜托。
Why is this so creepy?
为什么这如此令人毛骨悚然？
yes
是的
under both feet
双脚下
When this coffin was buried
当这口棺材被埋葬的时候
Yin energy is very strong.
阴气很强。
Many people today in the palace
今天皇宫里人很多
Made a mistake and was dragged out.
犯了一个错误，被拖了出去。
All were beaten to death alive.
全部被活活打死。
So the villagers rumoured.
于是，村民们纷纷议论。
that there is a devil haunting
有恶魔出没
underfoot
脚下
The person who died today
今天去世的人
Wear beautiful robes
穿上漂亮的长袍
There are many types of silk clothes on the body.
身上的丝绸衣服有很多种。
Plus there are those shoes.
另外还有那些鞋子。
Looking at it, I knew that it was very rich.
一看就知道很丰富。
You look.
你看。
instead of burning it
而不是烧掉它
It's better not to sell it to us for money.
最好不要为了钱卖给我们。
Do you guys dare to make money even from dead people?
你们连死人都敢赚钱吗？
No wonder there are people always spending money.
难怪有人总是花钱。
wise
明智的
I really want this job.
我真的很想要这份工作。
okay
好的
You guys make it a little nimble.
你们让它变得灵活一点。
yes
是的
Above has told me.
上面已经告诉我了。
that he must be seen by us
他必须被我们看到
burned to ashes with eyes
用眼睛烧成灰烬
Both of you are invited.
你们俩都被邀请了。
Hurry and change.
快点改变吧。
can
能
Hurry, hurry.
快点快点。
Hurry and walk.
快点走吧。
Hurry up.
赶快。
His Majesty
陛下
Has your body gotten better?
你的身体好起来了吗？
I'm not the eldest child. If you kill your father
我不是最大的孩子。如果你杀了你的父亲
I must thank you for being emperor.
我必须感谢你成为皇帝。
Is this what you wrote?
这是你写的吗？
yes
是的
His Majesty
陛下
You ungrateful son.
你这个忘恩负义的儿子。
You are an ungrateful son.
你真是个忘恩负义的儿子。
Are you really going to kill your father?
你真的要杀你的父亲吗？
Viceroy Sun was so cruel.
孙总督太残忍了。
You still want to be emperor.
你还想当皇帝。
You really want to kill me.
你真的想杀了我。
His Majesty
陛下
That was just a plan.
那只是一个计划。
Just provoke Sun Jing.
就去激怒孙静吧。
in order to help His Majesty come out
为了帮助陛下出来
Help me out.
帮帮我。
Where is this?
这是哪里？
This is Dan Tong.
这是童丹。
After Sun Jing rebelled,
孙敬叛乱后，
Father also
父亲也
locked up as a hostage I've always been in the capital.
我一直被当作人质关 在首都。
I'm always planning.
我总是在计划。
How to help Father come out
如何帮助父亲出来
previous
以前的
Arrange manpower secretly
秘密安排人手
in the palace
在宫殿里
through the Chui Sakul Army
通过 Chui Sakul 军
Just wait when the opportunity arises to take action.
只要等待机会出现就采取行动。
Well, when the opportunity arose, I took action.
好吧，当机会出现时，我就采取了行动。
Plan to act when your opportunity arises.
计划在机会出现时采取行动。
is to send an ungrateful letter
就是寄一封忘恩负义的信
Are you going to give it to Sun Jing?
你要送给孙静吗？
You know.
你知道。
If Sun Jing changed his mind just a little,
如果孙静稍微改变一下主意，
I'd probably have my head cut off.
我的头可能会被砍掉。
His Majesty
陛下
I know that after you saw the letter
我知道你看到这封信后
Must be extremely angry
一定非常愤怒
Your body has always been bad.
你的身体一直不好。
Often dizzy
经常头晕
I want you to be very angry.
我希望你非常生气。
You will immediately faint.
你会立即晕倒。
I ordered the drug user to fake death.
我命令吸毒者装死。
Makes his father look like he's dead. to fool Sun Jing
让他的父亲看上去就像死了一样。 糊弄孙静
Waiting for the body to be put in the coffin
等待尸体被放入棺材
Let the lily tree die instead of the peach tree.
让百合树死，而不是桃树死。
Then help Father come out.
然后扶爸爸出来。
You are ungrateful.
你忘恩负义。
You are an ungrateful son.
你真是个忘恩负义的儿子。
You act rashly and without thinking.
你行事鲁莽，不假思索。
You are taking your life.
你正在夺走你的生命。
of the father at birth
出生时父亲的
Become a bet, did you know?
成为赌注，你知道吗？
I don't dare.
我不敢。
What else do you not dare to do?
还有什么是你不敢做的呢？
I saw your face and I was angry.
我看到你的脸，我很生气。
Get over it.
克服它。
Hurry and get rid of your head.
快点把你的头去掉吧。
Yes, my child asks for leave.
是的，我的孩子请假。
Waiting for Father to stop being angry.
等待父亲不再生气。
I will come to visit you again.
我会再次来看你的。
Hurry and get rid of your head.
快点把你的头去掉吧。
Saluting the general
向将军致敬
I heard that Prince Liang has returned.
听说梁王回来了。
So I stewed a cup of chicken curry with pine mushrooms.
于是我就炖了一杯松茸咖喱鸡。
Scoop out the oil.
把油舀出来。
Make it a clear soup.
做成清汤。
I think Prince Liang
我觉得梁王
Going through hardships Tired both physically and mentally
历尽艰辛 身心疲惫
Eat light, nourishing food.
吃清淡、滋补的食物。
Can restore breath
可以恢复呼吸
Grandson probably doesn't know.
孙子大概不知道。
Our young lady
我们的少妇
Watch over the stove by yourself.
自己看管炉子。
Stewed for many hours
炖了好几个小时
Qiu Shui had already said too much.
秋水已经说得太多了。
It's difficult for you to get a loan.
你很难获得贷款。
What are these words, General?
将军，这些话是什么？
The general is a person who has to do big things.
将军是一个要干大事的人。
Busy with military activities
忙于军事活动
Sow Wattle is incompetent.
母猪荆棘无能。
And still a weak woman
还是一个弱女子
Adding to the suffering of the army
给军队增添苦难
Since Prince Liang has returned
梁王回来后
I asked the general to allow me to sow the wattles and take care of him.
我请求将军允许我播种荆棘并照顾他。
Prince Liang's clothes and food.
梁王的衣食。
this
这
It's better not to disturb Mr. Noo Loan.
最好不要打扰Noo Loan先生。
His father had just been rescued.
他的父亲刚刚获救。
My mind is still not stable.
我的心还不稳定。
Mood The mood was not good.
心情心情不太好。
General, don't worry.
将军，不用担心。
Sow wattles at home
在家播种肉垂
I used to take care of the elderly.
我以前是照顾老人的。
I know that my body is not good.
我知道我的身体不好。
suffering from illness
患病
It's normal to be in a bad mood.
心情不好是很正常的。
Commander, please rest assured.
指挥官，请放心。
Wan Niang will take care of Prince Liang.
万娘会照顾梁王的。
Definitely very good
绝对非常好
Yes, sir.
是的先生。
Our young lady is a detailed person.
我们的小姐姐是一个细节丰富的人。
At that time our master was sick.
那时我们的主人病了。
All of them are women who help take care of him.
他们都是帮助照顾他的女性。
Ask the general
询问将军
You can use it to sow wattles. What little abilities do you have?
您可以用它来播种肉垂。 你还有哪些小本领呢？
Like that, it's bothering you already.
就这样，它已经困扰你了。
Lady Taozi
桃子夫人
Has your wound gotten better?
你的伤口好了吗？
It's not a big deal.
没什么大不了的。
At most, it only hurt for a few days.
最多也就疼几天而已。
You must be hungry. Let's eat something.
你一定饿了。我们吃点东西吧。
come
来
can
能
What's the matter? Aren't the noodles delicious?
怎么了？面条不好吃吗？
How can water noodles be more delicious than pig ears?
水面怎么能比猪耳朵好吃呢？
What are you laughing at?
你在笑什么？
There's nothing.
什么也没有。
Mee is almost cold. You hurry up and eat.
梅几乎冷了。你赶紧吃饭吧。
(General's quarters)
（将军宿舍）
What are you doing secretly?
你在偷偷地做什么？
Do you want to secretly kiss me?
你想偷偷地吻我吗？
Do you have anything worthy of me secretly kissing?
你有什么值得我偷偷亲吻的吗？
This one.
这个。
I saved your life.
我救了你的命。
You think I helped you.
你以为我帮了你。
How many times?
多少次？
You act inconsiderate.
你表现得很不体贴。
A benefactor who saved your life like this?
恩人就这样救了你的命？
Grandson trusts
孙子信托
What day will you be in danger?
哪一天你会遇到危险？
I must eliminate all difficulties.
我必须排除一切困难。
Break through the thorns to help you.
冲破荆棘，助你一臂之力。
Polite people keep the truth. How delighted
有礼貌的人会讲真话。多么高兴
How do you know?
你怎么知道？
That someone wants to secretly attack us.
有人想暗中攻击我们。
I know Luoyang
我知道洛阳
Send out some troops.
派出一些军队。
And this force held the crossbow.
而这股力量握住了弩。
Clearly wanted to assassinate
明显是想刺杀
I thought about it.
我想过这个问题。
I suddenly thought of your Chui clan army.
我突然想到了你们崔氏军。
That Chui Li
那垂李
He had come to discuss with Pei Yuan.
他是来和裴渊商量的。
will secretly attack Khun Chai Chui
会暗中攻击Khun Chai Chui
I think
我认为
That Chui Li probably wouldn't.
那崔立大概不会。
Go do it with someone else.
去和别人一起做吧。
But go do it with Mr. Chui
但和崔先生一起去吧
Yes, Chui Li.
Yes, Chui Li.
It must be him.
一定是他。
And I don't know.
我不知道。
What method does he use?
他用什么方法呢？
that can give the people of Luoyang
可以给洛阳人民
Let him borrow your troops.
让他借用你的军队吧。
Since Chui Li wanted to kill Young Master Chui
既然崔离要杀崔公子
So you have to find someone.
所以你必须找人。
Let's blame him for the murder.
让我们把谋杀归咎于他吧。
During this time, I am at Dan Tong.
这段时间，我在丹童。
and was the commander of the Zhenxi Army.
并任镇西军司令。
Not the best option
不是最好的选择
expected
预期的
He probably used this method.
他大概就是用的这个方法。
Go convince my elder brother to borrow some troops.
去说服我哥哥借点兵力吧。
Your big brother?
你的大哥？
I couldn't imagine that they would do this.
我无法想象他们会这么做。
They are stupid and fuzzy.
他们既愚蠢又模糊。
It's normal to be easily deceived by people.
容易被人欺骗是很正常的。
The world is like this.
世界就是这样。
Chui Li was just
崔莉刚刚
Cousin of Aren't you all sirs?
表弟 你们不都是先生吗？
It is a quarrel between siblings.
这是兄弟姐妹之间的争吵。
It's definitely not good.
这绝对不好。
Things in Yingzhou must have secrets.
瀛州的事情必定有秘密。
What about you, sir? What about Taozi?
先生，你呢？桃子呢？
Are they injured?
他们受伤了吗？
And where is my horse?
我的马在哪里？
You probably can't.
你可能不能。
I'll hurry back to Yingzhou now.
我现在就赶紧回瀛州。
I'm worried.
我很担心。
Yingzhou is
瀛州是
The base of our Chui clan army.
我们崔氏军的基地。
Not working
不工作
I'll have to think of a way to hurry back.
我得想个办法赶紧回去。
Ah Ying
阿英
Your injuries are not fatal.
你的伤并不致命。
But your gentleman
但你的先生
May need to be rehabilitated well
可能需要好好康复
It's been several days.
已经好几天了。
If you insist on rushing back
如果你坚持要赶回来
I will not hinder you.
我不会妨碍你。
But you must think carefully.
但你必须仔细考虑。
that you can
你能行
endured until meeting a large army
一直忍到遇到大军
And there's still strength left.
而且还有力气。
Go help Ying Zhou again or not?
再去帮瀛洲吗？
Don't hurry.
别着急。
The matter has reached this stage.
事情已经发展到这个阶段了。
Don't fight us, let's think.
别跟我们作对，我们想一想。
Is there any other way?
还有其他办法吗？
sir
先生
Sir, you have recovered.
先生，您已经康复了。
What about Aing?
那艾英呢？
Khun Chai trusts
坤柴信托
The captain is fine.
队长很好。
Only minor injuries
仅受轻伤
It's not a big deal.
没什么大不了的。
Then that's good.
那就好了。
Ah, what?
啊，什么？
sir
先生
Ah, things are gone.
啊，东西没了。
Don't be sad.
别伤心。
protect sir
保护先生
It's our duty.
这是我们的职责。
But now
但现在
Ah, things no longer exist.
啊，东西已经不存在了。
Ah, things really no longer exist.
啊，东西真的不存在了。
sir
先生
Ah, things I probably didn't want. This gentleman is sad like this.
啊，我可能不想要的东西。 这位先生如此悲伤。
Me and Uncle Thing
我和东西叔叔
They were all orphans that no one wanted.
他们都是无人想要的孤儿。
If you don't have Mr.
如果你没有先生
with the captain who received us
和接待我们的船长
Let us be in the Chui clan army.
让我们在崔氏军中吧。
And where is there for us to live?
哪里有我们可以居住的地方？
I died for you.
我为你而死。
Ah, definitely no regrets.
啊，绝对不后悔。
I don't regret it either.
我也不后悔。
I cannot allow you to say these words.
我不能允许你说出这些话。
Where is this?
这是哪里？
Dan Tong
和桶
Zhenxi army camp
Zhenxi army camp
He is Dali's grandson.
他是达利的孙子。
Yes, it was him who brought us back.
是的，是他把我们带回来的。
Li Ni
李妮
sir
先生
You should rest first.
你应该先休息一下。
Just now, Tao Zi came to take the young man's pulse.
刚才，桃子过来给年轻人把脉。
Military doctor of the Zhenxi army
镇西军军医
I came to see your condition.
我是来看看你的情况的。
Said that the young man was seriously injured.
称这名年轻人伤势严重。
Must rest a lot.
一定要多休息。
no
不
I can't stay here.
我不能留在这里。
sir
先生
Urgent matters change according to the situation.
紧急事项根据情况而变化。
We have to recover well first.
我们首先要恢复得很好。
Plan again
重新计划
This place was still thousands of li away from Yingzhou.
此地距离瀛州还有数千里。
If a man doesn't take care of himself well
如果一个男人不能好好照顾自己
That's destruction.
那就是毁灭。
Placing all our pieces
放置我们所有的棋子
There is another matter.
还有一件事。
Chen thing
陈事
And the soldiers who fought to the death
还有那些战斗至死的战士们
of the Chui Sakul Army
崔萨库尔军
Please disturb my grandson and send someone to help me.
请打扰我的孙子并派人来帮助我。
bury them
埋葬他们
You trust me.
你信任我。
When you still haven't recovered
当你还没有康复的时候
I've sent someone to collect the corpse.
我已经派人去收尸了。
A soldier from the Chui army who fought until the death.
战斗至死的楚军战士。
I know that Chen things
我知道陈的事情
Be the bodyguard at your prince's side.
成为王子身边的贴身侍卫。
I've ordered people to go make spirit signs.
我已经命人去打灵符了。
Waiting for Mr. Chui to recover well.
等待崔先生康复。
Gradually go and pay homage by yourself.
渐渐自己去参拜。
Aing, I'm sorry.
阿英，对不起。
thank you
谢谢
come
来
When recovered
恢复时
You should be able to take medicine.
你应该能够吃药。
Taozi ordered me repeatedly.
桃子再三嘱咐我。
Let me keep an eye on you taking medicine.
让我留意你吃药的情况。
In order to prevent the wound from becoming pus-filled
为了防止伤口流脓
Very bitter
很苦
Lady Taozi
桃子夫人
I'm about to go find you.
我正要去找你。
What a coincidence!
真是巧合啊！
I'm about to go find it as well.
我也正想去找呢
What is the matter with you?
你怎么了？
This is a painkiller.
这是止痛药。
that I found for you
我为你找到的
You used it to put on wounds.
你用它来包扎伤口。
This way, you won't get hurt anymore.
这样，你就不会再受伤了。
fool
傻子
Have you forgotten?
你忘记了吗？
that I can administer the medicine myself
我可以自己用药
I definitely haven't forgotten.
我绝对没有忘记。
just
只是
I'm just afraid that if you don't exist,
我只是害怕如果你不存在
Last time you said
上次你说
Aren't your wounds going to hurt for many days?
你的伤口不会痛很多天吗？
Yes, then I will accept it.
是的，那我就接受。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
What is the matter with you?
你怎么了？
I'm looking for you.
我在找你。
Because I want you to help me.
因为我想让你帮助我。
What do you want me to do for you?
你想让我为你做什么？
just tell
只是告诉
I'll definitely help.
我一定会帮忙的。
Do you guys have any sugar?
你们有糖吗？
If it were honey
如果是蜂蜜的话
It'll be even better.
会更好。
sugar or
糖或
We fight and fight.
我们不断地战斗。
in the kitchen
在厨房
How can there be sugar?
怎么会有糖呢？
No need to mention honey at all.
根本不用提蜂蜜。
What do you want sugar for?
你要糖干什么？
our captain
我们的队长
Since I was little, after taking medicine
从小到大吃药后
I won't eat rice.
我不会吃米饭。
At that time, if there was sugar
那个时候如果有糖的话
After taking the medicine
服药后
Give her sweet water to drink.
给她喝甜水。
She's going to eat rice.
她要吃米饭。
But there's no market nearby.
但附近没有市场。
There is nowhere to buy.
没有地方可以买。
Prince Liang had reached Dan Tong safely.
梁王已安全抵达丹统。
Hopefully the grandson and heir to the throne will be able to Change bad things into good things.
希望孙子和王位继承人能够 把坏事变成好事。
Free from misfortune
远离不幸
Her Majesty trusts
女王陛下信任
The grandson and heir to the throne must be safe.
孙子和王位继承人必须安全。
Li Ni had captured Dan Tong.
Li Ni had captured Dan Tong.
It is expected that Sun Jing
预计孙静
The mind must be distraught.
心一定是心烦意乱的。
You look.
你看。
Today he had orders to harvest rice.
今天他接到命令去收割水稻。
to the people in the city
给这座城市的人们
Every family hoards
每个家庭都囤积
enough food to eat for three months
食物足够三个月吃
Sun Jing seemed to be preparing.
孙静似乎已经做好了准备。
For being surrounded
因为被包围
Thus, the seventeen grandchildren
于是，十七个孙子
Will he lead an army to surround the city?
他会率军围城吗？
Xichang City had a strong moat.
西昌城有坚固的护城河。
Easy to defend but difficult to attack.
守易攻难。
Li Ni would definitely not force his way in.
李妮绝对不会强行闯入。
hope
希望
Before Sun Jing
孙静之前
will call back the great army
将召回伟大的军队
Li Ni would be able to save Xichang City.
李妮一定能拯救西昌城。
Where have you gone and what have you done?
你去了哪里，做了什么？
I didn't even eat lunch.
我连午饭都没吃。
I just went for a walk on the mountain.
我刚刚去山上散步。
Shi Chi Lang
Shi Chi Lang
You are now a commander. of the Zhenxi Army
你现在是一名指挥官了。 镇西军
No matter what you do
无论你做什么
This cannot be done arbitrarily.
这不能随意进行。
Just like this time
就像这一次
You didn't care about the danger and went to help General He.
你不顾危险，前去帮助何将军。
Captain He is clever and cunning.
何队长聪明狡猾。
and was extremely loyal to Cuilin.
对翠琳极为忠诚。
A person like this will become a person sooner or later.
这样的人迟早会成为一个人。
It's definitely our downfall.
这绝对是我们的失败。
I think
我认为
She was more loyal to Cui Yi.
她对崔毅更加忠诚。
Do you think that
你认为
Between her and Mr. Chui
她和崔先生之间
How strange is that?
这有多奇怪？
What's strange?
有什么奇怪的？
That Captain He was loyal to Chui Lin.
那个何队长对翠琳是忠心耿耿的。
Or is he loyal to Cui Yi?
还是他对崔毅忠心耿耿？
It's the same.
一样的。
Father and son are like the same person.
父亲和儿子就像同一个人。
There are words that I shouldn't say.
有些话我不应该说。
But if
但如果
I'm not talking to you.
我不是在和你说话。
No one is talking to you anymore.
没有人再和你说话了。
Passionate, intoxicated, insane
热情、陶醉、疯狂
It is not the act of a polite person.
这不是一个有礼貌的人的行为。
You've misunderstood.
你误会了。
It's not what you think.
这不是你想的那样。
Shi Qi Lang, you look.
Shi Qi Lang, you look.
I'm prepared.
我准备好了。
I'll come back and talk to you soon.
我很快就会回来和你谈谈。
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
I won't tell you.
我不会告诉你。
♪If you forget the fleeting light of fireflies♪
♪如果你忘记了萤火虫那转瞬即逝的光芒♪
♪Waiting for memories♪
♪等待回忆♪
♪Shattered and drowned♪
♪破碎并淹死♪
♪Settled on the stain on your heart♪
♪解决了你心上的污点♪
♪That connection♪
♪那种联系♪
♪This is something I'm having a hard time letting go of♪
♪这是我很难放手的事情♪
♪If the anxiety never fades♪
♪如果焦虑永远不会消失的话♪
♪Return to the first time with regret♪
♪带着遗憾回到最初♪
♪The warmth that fate once had♪
♪命运曾经拥有的温暖♪
♪I want to keep it for you♪
♪我想为你保留它♪
♪If love remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪We made a promise♪
♪我们许下承诺♪
♪Even if this love hurts me♪
♪即使这份爱让我受伤♪
♪I will live for you♪
♪我会为你而活♪
♪Follow the outline in your memories♪
♪跟随记忆中的轮廓♪
♪Waiting for the person I cling to♪
♪等待我依恋的人♪
♪If love remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪Promises kept for you♪
♪对你的承诺♪
♪Change of cause and effect♪
♪因果的变化♪
♪I don't regret standing up for you♪
♪我不后悔为你挺身而出♪
♪I give up my desire for you♪
♪我放弃对你的渴望♪
♪Always waiting for you to answer me♪
♪永远等你回答我♪
♪If love remembers♪
♪如果爱还记得♪
♪Promises kept for you♪
♪对你的承诺♪
♪Change of cause and effect♪
♪因果的变化♪
♪I don't regret standing up for you♪
♪我不后悔为你挺身而出♪
♪I give up my desire for you♪
♪我放弃对你的渴望♪
♪Always waiting for you to answer me♪
♪永远等你回答我♪